<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>machine learning on felladog</title><link>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/categories/machine-learning/</link><description>Recent content in machine learning on felladog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 19:53:00 +0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>concept learning</title><link>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-06-04-14-08-26z-concept_learning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 19:53:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-06-04-14-08-26z-concept_learning/</guid><description>References : Reading: Tom Mitchell Lectures slides of chapter 2 Tom Mitchell, Machine Learning Chapter 2 Questions : Inferring boolean valued function from training examples of its input and outputs. A problem of searching through a predefined space of potential hypotheses for the hypothesis that best fits the training examples Example Traget concept or function: Concept or function to be learned.</description></item><item><title>Inductive Bias</title><link>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-06-03-11-07-01z-inductive_bias/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 16:52:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-06-03-11-07-01z-inductive_bias/</guid><description>References :
Reading: Tom Mitchell Lectures slides of chapter 2 Tom Mitchell, Machine Learning Chapter 2 To Read: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inductive%5Fbias Questions :
The inductive bias of a learning algorithm is the set of assumptions that the learner uses to predict outputs given inputs that it has not encountered.
Consider a concept learning algorithm L for the set of instances X.</description></item><item><title>regularization</title><link>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-05-26-11-28-39z-regularization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 17:13:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-05-26-11-28-39z-regularization/</guid><description>References :
To read: https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Regularization%5F(mathematics) https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Early%5Fstopping Questions :
In machine learning and regularization is the process of adding information in order to solve an ill-posed problem or to prevent overfitting.
Early Stopping Form of regularization used to avoid overfitting when training a learner with an iterative method, such as gradient descent. Such methods update the learner so as to make it better fit the training data with each iteration.</description></item></channel></rss>