<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>machine learning on felladog</title><link>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/categories/machine-learning/</link><description>Recent content in machine learning on felladog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 19:53:00 +0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>concept learning</title><link>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-06-04-14-08-26z-concept_learning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 19:53:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-06-04-14-08-26z-concept_learning/</guid><description>References : Reading: Tom Mitchell Lectures slides of chapter 2 Tom Mitchell, Machine Learning Chapter 2 To Read: Candidate elimination algorithm with an example Questions : Inferring boolean valued function from training examples of its input and outputs. A problem of searching through a predefined space of potential hypotheses for the hypothesis that best fits the training examples Example Traget concept or function: Concept or function to be learned.</description></item><item><title>Inductive Bias</title><link>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-06-03-11-07-01z-inductive_bias/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 16:52:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-06-03-11-07-01z-inductive_bias/</guid><description>References :
Reading: Tom Mitchell Lectures slides of chapter 2 Tom Mitchell, Machine Learning Chapter 2 To Read: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inductive%5Fbias Questions :
The inductive bias of a learning algorithm is the set of assumptions that the learner uses to predict outputs given inputs that it has not encountered.
Consider a concept learning algorithm L for the set of instances X.</description></item><item><title>decision tree</title><link>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-06-03-11-01-27z-decision_tree/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 16:46:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-06-03-11-01-27z-decision_tree/</guid><description>References :
Reading : Tom Mitchell Lectures slides of chapter 3 Tom Mitchell, Machine Learning Chapter 3 ID3 algorithm complete solution Reddit Post Link Drive Pdf Link To Read : Chapter 3 — Decision Tree Learning — Part 1 Questions :
Approximating discrete-valued fucntions robust to noisy data capable of learning disjunctive expressions search a completely expressive hypothesis space and thus avoid the difficulties of restricted hypothesis spaces.</description></item><item><title>regularization</title><link>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-05-26-11-28-39z-regularization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 17:13:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-05-26-11-28-39z-regularization/</guid><description>References :
To read: https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Regularization%5F(mathematics) https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Early%5Fstopping Questions :
In machine learning and regularization is the process of adding information in order to solve an ill-posed problem or to prevent overfitting.
Early Stopping Form of regularization used to avoid overfitting when training a learner with an iterative method, such as gradient descent. Such methods update the learner so as to make it better fit the training data with each iteration.</description></item><item><title>entropy</title><link>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-03-06-03-56-06z-entropy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 09:41:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/2021-03-06-03-56-06z-entropy/</guid><description>References :
https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Entropy%5F(information%5Ftheory) Entropy in image, scikit-image [3] https://bricaud.github.io/personal-blog/entropy-in-decision-trees/
Questions :
What is the point of entropy in decision tree? Entropy is a measure of disorder. A high entropy is essentially saying that the data is scattered around while a low entropy means that nearly all the data is the same. The highest entropy one can achieve is 1 and lowest entropy one can achieve is 0.</description></item><item><title>ML Model Evaluation</title><link>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/20210224162319-model_evaluations_score/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 16:23:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/20210224162319-model_evaluations_score/</guid><description>references To Read: https://towardsdatascience.com/handling-imbalanced-datasets-in-machine-learning-7a0e84220f28 questions ml model evaluation methods
Classfication True Positive (TP) Positive class correctly labeled/predicted False Negative (FN) Positive class incorrectly labeled/predicted False Positive (FP) Negative class incorrectly labeled/predicted True Negative (TN) Negative class correctly labeled/predicted Accuracy It is simply a ratio of correctly predicted observation to the total observations.</description></item><item><title>machine learning</title><link>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/20210119123811-machine_learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 17:28:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://utsavdarlami.github.io/blogs/notes/20210119123811-machine_learning/</guid><description>references Reading https://www.cs.cmu.edu/~tom/mlbook.html To Read https://medium.com/octavian-ai/how-to-get-started-with-machine-learning-on-graphs-7f0795c83763 https://medium.datadriveninvestor.com/3-steps-introduction-to-machine-learning-and-design-of-a-learning-system-bd12b65aa50c https://chrisalbon.com/ A computer program is said to learn from experience E with respect to some class of tasks T and performance measure P, if its performance at tasks in T, as measured by P, improves with experience E.
A checkers learning problem: Task T: playing checkers Performance measure P: percent of games won against opponents Training experience E: playing practice games against itself Supervised Lecture 1: Supervised Learning regression classfication Unsupervised clustering dimensionality reduction ML Model Evaluation Graph Based Resources Pandas Guide , axis = https://stackoverflow.</description></item></channel></rss>